Eric Vincent

4237 Manuela Ave | Palo Alto, CA 94306 | evincent@gmail.com | eqvincent.github.io | 650 468 0664

Education Stanford University

Class of 2020

Stanford, CA

Selected current and completed courses:

- CS 106X: Programming Abstractions Accelerated (advanced C++ foundational class)
- Breaking Codes & Finding Patterns (encryption; introductory information theory and number theory)
- CS 107: Computer Organization and Systems (C, data representation, machine-level code, computer arithmetic, and memory)
- CS 110: Principles of Computer Systems (filesystems, concurrency, networking)

Henry M. Gunn High School

Class of 2016

Palo Alto, CA

Selected completed courses: AP Biology, AP AB Calculus, Programming Concepts (in Scheme), Introduction to Java, AP French, AP Micro/Macroeconomics

GPA: 3.79 unweighted, 3.96 weighted

SAT: 730 reading, 700 math, 760 writing (2190 total)

Institute for Mathematics and Computer Science 2013 - 2014 Online AP Computer Science: Java Programming (not allowed for sophomores at Gunn HS) *Grade:* A+, *AP Test Score:* 5 out of 5

Experience

<u>DeepMap</u>

Intern

Summer of 2017

San Mateo Gymnastics

Palo Alto, CA

DeepMap provides high definition 3D mapping as a service for self-driving cars.

Savioke Intern Summer of 2016 San Jose, CA Savioke builds the Relay, an autonomous, user-friendly room service robot for hotels.

- Enabled Relay robot to call external APIs
- Connected Relay to Amazon Alexa and the Amazon IOT Button
- Explored new interactive uses for Relay by using/extending visual robot scripting interface.
- Used: AWS, JavaScript with MeteorJS and ROS, Google Blockly

<u>Metanautix</u> (acquired by Microsoft) Intern Summer of 2015 Palo Alto, CA Enterprise software company focused on big data management, analytics, and visualization.

- Front-end web developer
- Used: AngularJS and Bootstrap

<u>Camio</u> Intern Summer of 2014 San Mateo, CA

Smart, cloud-based video monitoring and analytics for the home.

- Automatic graphing of company metrics
- Used: JavaScript and Google BigQuery with SQL

	Foothills Summer Camp	Counselor	Summer of 2012	Foothills Park
Activities	Competitive Gymnastics	2007 - 2016	Stanford Boys	Gymnastics,

I was a competitive gymnast for nine years. I practiced ~20 hours per week year round. I was team captain from 2015 to 2016.

Highlights:

Level 10 (2016) – JO Nationals: 5th place and all around finals. Regionals: 6th place and all-star team. States: 2nd place and all-star team.

Level 9 (2011-2013) – JO Nationals all three years, event finals on floor and pommel horse Level 6 (2009) – 4th place at State Championships, 1st place at Regional Championships.

Gunn Robotics Team

2014 - 2016

www.gunnrobotics.com

I was a member of my school's student-run FIRST robotics team for two years, and a member of the team's control systems group for one year. I have experience machining on a mill, lathe, drill press, band saw, and many other shop tools. In the controls group, I wrote python code to access several sensors and to control several mechanisms on the robot. I was an active member, and contributed upwards of 10 hours per week in addition to attending the competitions, helping our team win the FRC Team Spirit Award last year. In addition to coding and machining, I have written content for our team's website and business plan and have experience with CAD and basic electrical engineering.

Ecole Nationale du Cirque

2010 - 2012

ecolenationaledecirque.ca/en

I was accepted at the prestigious "National Circus School" in Montreal, Canada for three consecutive summers. While at the school I improved my skills in hand balancing, unicycling, and learned the German Wheel, Silks, and other disciplines of circus arts.

Graphic Arts, Stanford Open

2011 - 2015

egvincent.com/stanford-open

For the past 5 years I have designed the T-shirt and logo for the "Stanford Open," an annual three-day gymnastics competition my gym hosts for over 800 gymnasts and their families.

Programming Skills

 Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C++, JSON, Bash, Python, and several other languages. Familiar with tools such as Git, Robot Framework, Bootstrap, jQuery, and AngularJS

Some of my side projects include:

- My personal website eqvincent.com, and several other front-end projects
- A working platformer-style game in the Unity game development environment with art I worked on with a friend
- A game of "snake" and "pong" in JavaScript (snake located at eqvincent.com/snake)

Awards	AP Scholar with Distinction	2016	CollegeBoard
	Academic All American Recognition Award	2015: First Team honors 2014: Second Team honors	USA Gymnastics
	French National Contest	2013 (2C): Lauréat du Chapitre and Certificat d'Honneur	The American Association of Teachers of French
	Outstanding Accomplishments in the Visual Arts	2015	Gunn High School